A very popular strategy for gambling used
轮盘赌等有一个很流行的赌博策略
with Roulette and other games is called the Martingale strategy.
叫马丁格尔策略
You start betting small and every time you lose,
从小赌注开始 每输一次
you play again betting double as much as the previous bet.
你就把赌注翻一倍 再下注
And when you actually win you make up for all the losses you've
这样等你赢了 你不仅能弥补之前所有的损失
suffered so far plus a small profit thanks to that double bet strategy.
而且由于这个赌注翻倍的策略 你还能小赚一笔
Which means you can now reset your bet back to
也就是说现在你可以将赌注重置成
that small starting bet and start all over again.
一开始的小数额 然后重新开始游戏了
This strategy assumes that you would eventually
这个策略的思路是 随着时间积累
build up all those small profits over time.
你最终能靠那些小赢积累出一笔财富
But the danger is that you could easily run out of money.
但风险就是 钱很容易就会赌完
Because you're doubling your bet every time,
因为你每次都得把赌注翻一倍
money would run out real fast.
所以钱会花得很快
The key now is to know when to stop.
因此 现在关键就是要知道何时该停止
Let's assume you're going to start with
假设你一开始有一千美元
a thousand dollars and you'd be really happy if you can make a 20% profit,
如果你能在这个基础上赚 20% 你就满意了
meaning that you would end up with $12,000.
也就是说 最后你会有 1200 美元
However, the minimum bet that you can play is $10.
不过 最小的一注是 10 美元
So to get there, you start with this minimum bet of
所以要达成目标 你需要从 10 美元这个最小赌注开始玩
$10 and you would keep doubling every time you lose,
每输一次就把赌注翻一倍
but reset it back to 10 once you win.
一旦赢了就把赌注重设为 10
Here's the function called martingale.
这个函数 martingale
It doesn't have any input parameters,
没有任何输入参数
but it returns the integer,
但是会返回一个整数
which is the value of the money you end up with,
也即最后你拥有的金额
which could be either more than what you started with or a lot less.
可能会比一开始多 也可能会少很多
The first thing we do is we start with initializing those three variables here: money,
首先我们需要初始化这三个变量
target and bet, equal to those values.
money 、target 和 bet 使其等于这些值
And then we have this while loop.
然后就是这个 while 循环
The idea of this loop is that it would keep repeating this code block down
这个循环的思路是 重复执行下面这个代码块
here for as long as we still have enough money to place a bet.
直到我们不够钱下注
So as long as money is greater than bet.
所以条件是 money 大于 bet
Once we don't have enough money anymore,
一旦我们钱不够了
then we just return whatever money we have.
无论我们剩下多少钱 函数都会把这个数额返回出来
Inside that loop, we're using this function called play.
在循环里 我们使用的这个函数叫 play
This function simulates the actual betting game play.
该函数模拟了真实的赌博游戏
Assume it's implemented somewhere else and it returns a boolean.
假设函数在其它地方实现并返回了布尔值
This boolean is true if you've won that bet and false if you didn't.
如果你赢了赌注 布尔值就为真 如果输了 布尔值就为假
So we're storing the return value of this function into the variable win here,
接着我们将这个函数的返回值赋给这里的变量 win
which is a boolean, and we're checking if we actually did win this bet or not.
这是个布尔变量 然后我们来判断是否赢了这个赌注
If we did, we just add the bet value to our money and then reset it back to 10.
如果赢了 就将 bet 的值和 money 相加 然后将 bet 重置为 10
If we didn't win this bet,
如果输了
we subtract it from our money value and then we
那就从 money 的值中减去 bet 的值
multiply the actual bet by two so that we double the bet for the next time.
然后将实际赌注乘以二 这样在下一轮赌注就翻倍了
This code block here would keep repeating
这个代码块会不断重复执行
until we don't have enough money to bet anymore.
直到我们不够钱下注为止
Now there is one part missing here.
现在这里少了一部分
We need to break out of this loop when it's time to stop
我们需要在该停止游戏的时候跳出这个循环
playing and that's when we've reached our target that we're happy with.
也就是当我们实现了令自己满意的目标时 就跳出循环
Modify this code here by adding an IF condition that
修改这段代码 给它加一个 if 条件
checks if the money has reached or exceeded our predefined target.
检查 money 是否达到或超过了我们定下的目标
And if so, break from this loop.
如果是 那就跳出循环